<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Redis on Billy Petersson - IT Professional Portfolio</title><link>https://peterssontech.net/tags/redis/</link><description>Recent content in Redis on Billy Petersson - IT Professional Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peterssontech.net/tags/redis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>E-Commerce Platform</title><link>https://peterssontech.net/projects/ecommerce-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterssontech.net/projects/ecommerce-platform/</guid><description>E-Commerce Platform A comprehensive e-commerce solution built with modern web technologies, featuring real-time inventory management, secure payment processing, and a powerful admin dashboard.
Overview This project was developed to demonstrate full-stack development capabilities and showcase modern e-commerce features. The platform handles everything from product catalog management to order processing and customer analytics.
Key Features Customer-Facing Features Responsive Product Catalog - Browse products with advanced filtering and search Real-time Inventory Updates - Live stock levels and availability notifications Secure Checkout Process - Multi-step checkout with payment validation User Account Management - Registration, login, order history, and wishlist Product Reviews &amp;amp; Ratings - Customer feedback system with moderation Mobile-First Design - Optimized for all device types Admin Dashboard Inventory Management - Add, edit, and track products with bulk operations Order Management - Process orders with status tracking and notifications Customer Analytics - Detailed insights into customer behavior and sales Sales Reporting - Comprehensive reports with data visualization Content Management - Manage product descriptions, images, and categories User Role Management - Different access levels for staff and administrators Technical Features Real-time Updates - WebSocket integration for live inventory and notifications Payment Processing - Stripe integration with support for multiple payment methods Security - JWT authentication, input validation, and secure data handling Performance - Optimized queries, caching, and image optimization Scalability - Microservices architecture ready for horizontal scaling Technical Architecture Frontend (React) State Management - Redux Toolkit for complex state management Routing - React Router with protected routes and lazy loading UI Components - Custom component library with consistent design system Form Handling - React Hook Form with validation and error handling Data Fetching - React Query for efficient API calls and caching Backend (Node.</description></item><item><title>Analytics Dashboard</title><link>https://peterssontech.net/projects/analytics-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterssontech.net/projects/analytics-dashboard/</guid><description>Analytics Dashboard A comprehensive real-time analytics platform that transforms raw data into actionable insights through customizable dashboards, advanced visualizations, and automated reporting.
Overview This project was developed to address the growing need for real-time data visualization and analytics in modern businesses. The platform provides a flexible, scalable solution for monitoring key performance indicators and generating business intelligence reports.
Key Features Dashboard Management Customizable Widgets - Drag-and-drop interface for building personalized dashboards Real-time Data Updates - Live data streaming with WebSocket connections Multi-tenant Support - Isolated workspaces for different teams and organizations Responsive Design - Optimized for desktop, tablet, and mobile viewing Dashboard Templates - Pre-built templates for common use cases Export Capabilities - Export dashboards as PDFs or images Data Visualization Interactive Charts - Dynamic charts with zoom, pan, and drill-down capabilities Multiple Chart Types - Line, bar, pie, heatmap, scatter, and custom visualizations Data Filtering - Advanced filtering options with date ranges and custom criteria Comparative Analysis - Side-by-side comparisons and trend analysis Geospatial Visualization - Map-based data representation with geographic insights Custom Metrics - User-defined calculations and aggregations Reporting &amp;amp; Automation Scheduled Reports - Automated report generation and delivery Alert System - Threshold-based notifications and anomaly detection Data Export - CSV, Excel, and JSON export options API Integration - RESTful API for programmatic access Webhook Support - Real-time notifications for external systems Audit Trail - Complete logging of user actions and data changes Technical Architecture Frontend (Vue.</description></item></channel></rss>