<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech Blog on Billy Petersson - IT Professional Portfolio</title><link>https://peterssontech.net/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Tech Blog on Billy Petersson - IT Professional Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peterssontech.net/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kubernetes Deployment Strategies for Modern Applications</title><link>https://peterssontech.net/blog/kubernetes-deployment-strategies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterssontech.net/blog/kubernetes-deployment-strategies/</guid><description>Kubernetes Deployment Strategies for Modern Applications As organizations scale their containerized applications, choosing the right deployment strategy becomes crucial for maintaining high availability and minimizing user impact during updates. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore various Kubernetes deployment strategies and when to use each one.
Why Deployment Strategies Matter Deploying applications in production environments requires careful consideration of factors like:
Zero-downtime requirements Rollback capabilities Resource utilization Testing requirements Risk tolerance The right deployment strategy can mean the difference between seamless updates and catastrophic outages.</description></item><item><title>React Performance Optimization: Best Practices for 2024</title><link>https://peterssontech.net/blog/react-performance-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterssontech.net/blog/react-performance-optimization/</guid><description>React Performance Optimization: Best Practices for 2024 As React applications grow in complexity, performance optimization becomes crucial for maintaining a smooth user experience. This comprehensive guide covers modern techniques and best practices for optimizing React applications in 2024.
Understanding React Performance Before diving into optimization techniques, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand how React works and where performance bottlenecks typically occur.
React&amp;rsquo;s Reconciliation Process React uses a virtual DOM and a reconciliation algorithm to efficiently update the UI.</description></item><item><title>Python Automation: From Repetitive Tasks to Production Workflows</title><link>https://peterssontech.net/blog/python-automation-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peterssontech.net/blog/python-automation-guide/</guid><description>Python Automation: From Repetitive Tasks to Production Workflows Python&amp;rsquo;s simplicity and extensive library ecosystem make it an excellent choice for automation. This comprehensive guide will take you from basic task automation to building sophisticated production workflows.
Why Python for Automation? Python excels at automation because of:
Readable syntax that makes scripts easy to maintain Rich standard library covering most common tasks Extensive third-party packages for specialized operations Cross-platform compatibility for diverse environments Strong community support and documentation 1.</description></item></channel></rss>